<?xml version="1.0" standalone="yes"?>
<rss xmlns:sparkle="http://www.andymatuschak.org/xml-namespaces/sparkle" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Spectrum</title>
        <item>
            <title>3.3.0-beta</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2024 13:26:16 +0100</pubDate>
            <sparkle:version>465</sparkle:version>
            <sparkle:shortVersionString>3.3.0-beta</sparkle:shortVersionString>
            <sparkle:minimumSystemVersion>12.0</sparkle:minimumSystemVersion>
            <description><![CDATA[<title>Version 3.3.0 (Build 465)</title>
<description>
	This is a beta version which probably has not been sufficiently tested.
	<ul>
		<li> Version 3.3.0 (465):
			<ul>
    		    <li> Includes the definition for the DDA instrument, ready for importing scope data generated by the EM.
    		    <li> Includes an updated CDA instrument definition.
    		    <li> Updates the conversion tables for CDA raw data.
    		    <li> The app silently recreates missing DN data for instruments which use conversion tables.
				<li> DN as y axis unit can now only be selected for appropriate instruments.
    		    <li> The Instrument dialog now saves gain stage definition changes.
    		    <li> The Instrument dialog now verifies whether an instrument family already exists.
    		    <li> Many bug fixes.
    		</ul>
		<li> Version 3.3.0 (464):
			<ul>
    		    <li> Migrated the Impact data base access dialogs to SwiftUI. With that the migration to SwiftUI is complete.
   				<li> Improved the Impact Query dialog. The dialog clearly indicates if Spice ressources must be loaded first to enable a correct conversion of the event time.
   				<li> Added a context menu to the Query dialog to enable easier builds of range constraints (e.g. time ≥ x && time ≤ y).
   				<li> Other bug fixes.
    		</ul>
		<li> Version 3.3.0 (463):
			<ul>
    		    <li> The spreadsheet editor has been merged with the CSV export file dialog.
   				<li> Other bug fixes.
    		</ul>
		<li> Version 3.3.0 (462):
    		<ul>
    		    <li> Reorganized the Import menu in the menu bar. 
    		    <li> Fixed crashes associated with file selection dialogs.
    		    <li> Other bug fixes.
    		</ul>
		<li> Version 3.3.0 (Build 460):
			<ul>
				<li> Excludes events with clipped QD feature from Grid Statistics analysis.
				<li> Includes all bug fixes in the current stable branch (3.2.6).
			</ul>
		<li> Version 3.3.0 (Build 456):
			<ul>
		    	<li> Columns of all Viewer tables can be rearranged by the user (only supported in MacOS 14 Sonoma). A right click into the column's header opens a menu for downselecting columns.
		    	<li> Includes all bug fixes in the current stable branch (3.2.4).
			</ul>
		<li> Version 3.3.0 (Build 454):
			<ul>
		    	<li> Columns of the Spectrum and Line Viewer tables can be rearranged by the user (only supported in MacOS 14 Sonoma).
		    	<li> Implemented a work around to prevent crashes when starting an import on Intel Macs. Please note that I couldn't 
		    	     test this on an Intel Mac so far.
			</ul>      
	</ul>
</description>
]]></description>
            <enclosure url="https://impact.colorado.edu/Spectrum-beta.zip" length="77584993" type="application/octet-stream" sparkle:edSignature="lUVpkon6amlyaJcCB4lrlgzXBKA4L8dtVH+m/aqoZhg0isciRd4/hyY8BsOdcuXHkjBwNJUCzlT/ujKNP7V+Cw=="/>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>