<?xml version="1.0" standalone="yes"?>
<rss xmlns:sparkle="http://www.andymatuschak.org/xml-namespaces/sparkle" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Spectrum</title>
        <item>
            <title>3.2.0-beta</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2023 16:16:12 -0700</pubDate>
            <sparkle:version>435</sparkle:version>
            <sparkle:shortVersionString>3.2.0-beta</sparkle:shortVersionString>
            <sparkle:minimumSystemVersion>12.0</sparkle:minimumSystemVersion>
            <description><![CDATA[<title>Version 3.2.0 (Build 434)</title>
<description>
	This is a beta version which probably has not been sufficiently tested.
	<ul>	
		 <li> Version 3.2.0 (Build 435):
		    <ul>
		 		<li> Migration to SwiftUI mostly complete. This will (eventually) improve the stability and performance of the App.
		 	</ul>	
	 	 <li> Version 3.2.0 (Build 434):
		  		<ul>
		  	 		<li> Full migration of the main data viewers (Spectrum, Lines, ...) from Cocoa to SwiftUI, which will (eventually)
		  	 		     improve the stability of the software. The changes to the user interface itself may appear minor, but the 
		  	 		     changes under the hood are massive.  
		  	 		<li> The onboarding part of the software has been reviewed and partially rewritten. Fresh installations should 
		  	 		     now running out of the box. The internal reference database can be reset to default to recover broken 
		  	 		     installations.
		  	 		<li> Imports BCE7 data.
		  		</ul>	
		 <li> Version 3.2.0 (Build 433):
		  		<ul>
		  	 		<li> This version ignores the incorrectly formed CCSDS headers generated by the current IDEX FSW. 
		  	 		<li> Added IDEX 2 to the default instrument set. Please use this version to import IDEX instrument packets.
		  		</ul>	
		<li> Version 3.2.0 (Build 431):
		  		<ul>
		  			<li> Imports IDEX CCSDS packets.
		  			<li> Removed Packet Analyzer and Catalog Viewer, Please use PacketAnalyzer instead.
		  			<li> Migrated more components to SwiftUI
		  		</ul>	
		<li> Version 3.2.0 (Build 427):
		  		<ul>
		  			<li> Fixes an issue where the selection of Rise Time as color code may lead to a crash.
	     		</ul>	
		 <li> Version 3.2.0 (Build 426):
		  		<ul>
	      	 		<li> Can fix in some cases a damaged internal database. 
					<li> Fixes an issue where a reassignment of a gain stage waveform to a spectrum was not apparent.
					<li> Improves assignment of shift parameters.
		  		</ul>	
		<li> Version 3.2.0 (Build 425):
		  		<ul>
					<li> Migrated the Composition Types, Target, and Material Catalogs to SwiftUI.
			 		<li> Brought back paste and copy to catalog dialogs.
			 		<li> Improved code stability.	
				</ul>	
		 <li> Version 3.2.0 (Build 421):
		  		<ul>
			 		<li> Added a roadmap dialog which allows users to vote on features to be added.
			 		<li> Migrated the Line Catalog and Cluster Dialog to SwiftUI.
			 		<li> Fixed an issue which affected the selection of CCSDS files for import.
	 			</ul>	
			<li> Version 3.2.0 (Build 421):
		  		<ul>
			 		<li> Fixes an issue where an Impact DB script was not correctly executed.
				</ul>
		<li> Version 3.2.0 (Build 420):
		  		<ul>
			 		<li> Fixes an issue where the library selection did not work in the Line Type Library UI.
			 		<li> Addresses an rare issue that affected the import of damaged or incomplete accelerator scope traces.
			 		<li> Caches results of line type calculations, which rapidly get computationally expensive for larger molecules.
					 <li> Improved code stability
				</ul>	
		<li> Version 3.2.0 (Build 417):
			<ul>
				<li> Supports scripted Impact data base queries. 
				<li> Adds ice accelerator dust source.
				<li> Adds ability to invert TOF waveforms.
			</ul>	
		<li> Version 3.1.0 (416): 
       		 <ul>
       		 	<li> New Impact Database account management, which moved to the Preferences dialog. Account credentials will be stored in the user's local keychain, implying that passwords only need entered at the time of the account's registration with the app. Accounts can be selected in the main menu's Impact menu.
       		 	<li> Supports Impact database version 3.4.0, which now accepts QD (accelerator) data. Ignored and locked state of mass lines are now exported to Impact DB. 
	    		<li> Impact Database action menus have been moved to stand alone menu Impact located in the main menu bar.
	    		<li> Import and Export submenues have been moved from File menu to main bar.
	    		<li> The H5 export has been significantly enhanced to allow for the reimport of H5 files. Import of H5 Spectrum archives are now possible. H5 archives starting with a LILBID group are considered to contain LILBID raw data generated by the Freie University group and will be coverted into a Spectrum project.
	        	<li> This version brings support of user-defined Python functions. Right now Python modules computing line shapes and waveform models can be called by Spectrum. Python plugins need to registered via the Preferences dialog. Because Spectrum is sandboxed, it cannot call call external programs including the Python interpreter. For this reason, a full Python 3.8 package including NumPy is bundled into the App (which explains the large increase of the app's size).
	    		<li> Impproved import of PSU data. The correlation between PSU and QD data can be analysed indepth with the new QD Detection Statistics tool.
	    		<li> New tool for visualizing the impact plasma composition as function of the impact speed, impact energy, and impact energy density.
	    		<li> Suports lastest version of SUDA instrument software. 					
	    		<li> Provides predefined IDEX and DDA instruments.
	        	<li> Improved code stability
	        	<li> Known issues:
	        		<ul>
	        			<li> Data sets containing complex large molecules are causing performance issues. This problem has been fixed in 3.2.0 (beta).
	        		</ul>
	   		</ul>	
	</ul>
</description>
]]></description>
            <enclosure url="https://impact.colorado.edu/Spectrum-beta.zip" length="76432753" type="application/octet-stream" sparkle:edSignature="ARqMo9qVWpEYXNgzpY3w8u5PxsbyA7CBli0K+zlzuw7IqLRfKai8PfoixsrGSCZatYBzj4LlxbyEW1kznLkTCQ=="/>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>