<?xml version="1.0" standalone="yes"?>
<rss xmlns:sparkle="http://www.andymatuschak.org/xml-namespaces/sparkle" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Spectrum</title>
        <item>
            <title>3.3.0-beta</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2024 14:18:17 +0100</pubDate>
            <sparkle:version>494</sparkle:version>
            <sparkle:shortVersionString>3.3.0-beta</sparkle:shortVersionString>
            <sparkle:minimumSystemVersion>12.0</sparkle:minimumSystemVersion>
            <description><![CDATA[<title>Version 3.3.0 (Build 494)</title>
<description>
	This is a beta version which probably has not been sufficiently tested.
	<ul>
		<li> Version 3.3.0 (494):
			<ul>
				<li> Shows the molecular structure of molecules for which a SMILES string has been provided.
				<li> Fixed various issues which affected the IMPACT Query dialog.
			</ul>
		<li> Version 3.3.0 (493):
			<ul>
				<li> Fixed an issue that prevented the Line Viewer's Mass Range Dialog from closing.
				<li> Fixed an issue which prevented newly defined Line type definitions from being added to the reference library.
				<li> Added Deletion Confirmation Dialogs to the Catalog Definition Dialogs.
				<li> Improved the Line Type Ratio statistics viewer.
				<li> Updates the default line types definitions after an increase of the app version.
			</ul>
		<li> Version 3.3.0 (491):
			<ul>
				<li> Improved the default heavy water line catalog and template.
				<li> Fixed some UI issues in the Spectrum Template Dialog
				<li> Fixed the save reminder dialog of the catalog viewers.
			</ul>
		<li> Version 3.3.0 (491):
	    	<ul>
				<li> Deuterium can now be used like a chemical element when defining an 
				     ion molecule. This enables the definition of e.g. heavy water clusters.
				     To this aim, a heavy water line catalog and a heay water template are
				     now included in the default catalog set.
				<li> Better handling of isotopologues. The main isotopologue is added to the
				     set of line type parameters.
				<li> Cleaned and verfied the default reference database.
				<li> Redesigned the Line Catalog and the Database Maintainance dialogs.
				<li> Redesigned the Line Type Editor.
				<li> Fixed various bugs in the Line Catalog and the Line Type Editor.
				<li> Bug fixes.
			</ul>
		<li> Version 3.3.0 (489):
	    	<ul>
				<li> This release brings the long promised support for ice targets. For such targets the
					 solvent and up to 3 solutes can be selected from a (yet) rather small list of chemical
					 compounds (including water, ammonia, methanol, and NaCl).
				<li> The new target types are supported by the IMPACT data base.
				<li> Optimized the project setup UI. Reorganized the processing pane.
				<li> Fixed an issue with the focusing of the selected line in line tables.
				<li> Bug fixes.
			</ul>
		<li> Version 3.3.0 (486):
	    	<ul>
				<li> Improved the setup of Spice kernels to load. You can now either load the kernels using
					 meta kernel, or you can select individual kernels via a user interface.
				<li> Fixed the highlighting of selected table rows.
			</ul>
		<li> Version 3.3.0 (485):
	    	<ul>
				<li> Line viewer now supports fitting of sum spectra line (set sum spectra button located 
				     above spectra table).
			</ul>
		<li> Version 3.3.0 (484):
	    	<ul>
				<li> Fixed an issue where line types not included in the project's line catalog but assigned
				     to a line lead to a crash when bringing up the line popup menu. 
				<li> Changes to line type definitions are now saved.
			</ul>
	    <li> Version 3.3.0 (483):
	    	<ul>
				<li> Fixed the frequent mystery crashes introduced by the new Swift toolchain. The root cause
				     for the crashes is the Swift optimizer, which has been disabled for now. 
				<li> Rewrote the Spice toolkit integration, which fixes many issues reported by users. The 
				     Spice error messages are now more helpful. The app is now using the most recent Spice 
				     release N0067.
				<li> Fixed the fitting of CDA waveforms.
				<li> Improved response to selection changes.
				<li> Bug fixes and performance improvments.
			</ul>
		<li> Version 3.3.0 (478):
			<ul>
				<li> Fixed an issue where identically named composition types catalogs may cause a crash.
				<li> Improved import of CCSDS packets.
				<li> Other bug fixes.
			</ul>
		<li> Version 3.3.0 (477):
			<ul>
				<li> Fixed an issue where removing a spectrum caused a crash.
				<li> Reorganized the QD processing menu. Added the capability to trim QD waveforms in the time domain. 
				<li> Other bug fixes.
			</ul>
		<li> Version 3.3.0 (476):
			<ul>
				<li> Computation of a sum spectrum will not any longer crash the app.
				<li> Other bug fixes.
			</ul>
		<li> Version 3.3.0 (475):
			<ul>
				<li> Fixed another issue in the Impact query filter UI. Selecting time ranges do not crash any longer.
				<li> Rewrote Run Script query UI. Swift meta kernels will now be loaded before executing the query.
				<li> Known issues:
					<ul>
						<li> Computing sum spectra will lead to a crash.
						<li> Running Impact query cannot be canceled.
					</ul>
			</ul>
		<li> Version 3.3.0 (474):
			<ul>
				<li> Fixed issue in Impact query filter UI.
				<li> Improved field dropdown menu in Impact query UI.
			</ul>
		<li> Version 3.3.0 (473):
			<ul>
				<li> Supports upcomming MacOS 15.
				<li> Filter dialog works on MacOS 12.
				<li> Minor UI tweaks.
			</ul>
		<li> Version 3.3.0 (472):
			<ul>
				<li> Fixed Target dialog.
				<li> As a fallback for MacOS 12 users, the accounts dialog has been added to the Impact menu.
			</ul>
		<li> Version 3.3.0 (471):
			<ul>
				<li> Fixed Template dialog.
				<li> Fixed Materials dialog.
				<li> Other bug fixes.
			</ul>
		<li> Version 3.3.0 (470):
			<ul>
				<li> Bug fixes.
			</ul>
		<li> Version 3.3.0 (469):
			<ul>
				<li> Fixed an issue with the updater in MacOS 14.
				<li> A few bug bug fixes. 
			</ul>
		<li> Version 3.3.0 (468):
			<ul>
				<li> The method for culling waveforms with a large number of sampling points for generating plots can 
				     be selected in the Settings dialog. High mass resolution spectra need to use more computationally
				     expensive methods to preserve narrow features in plots.
				<li> Focusing lens voltages can be defined in the project setup.
				<li> Rewrote the scope data import dialog.
				<li> Tips for using the scope import dialog will be shown infrequently.
				<li> Electrodes can be added again in the instrument dialog.
				<li> Various bug fixes. 
			</ul>
		<li> Version 3.3.0 (467):
			<ul>
				<li> Uses the most recent version of PacketCrusher which is more forgiving when importing SUDA CCSDS data.
				<li> Fixes issues with the line catalog user interface introduced in one of the previous releases.
				     Line types can be copied and edited again!
				<li> Fixed issues with the interfacing for writing chemical formulas.
			</ul>
		<li> Version 3.3.0 (466):
			<ul>
				<li> On MacOS 14 the side bar is back on the right side of the app.
				<li> Fixed some minor work flow issues.
				<li> Fixed the zooming state of the accelerator data viewer.
				<li> Fixes some of the default instrument definitions.
			</ul>
		<li> Version 3.3.0 (465):
			<ul>
    		    <li> Includes the definition for the DDA instrument, ready for importing scope data generated by the EM.
    		    <li> Includes an updated CDA instrument definition.
    		    <li> Updates the conversion tables for CDA raw data.
    		    <li> The app silently recreates missing DN data for instruments which use conversion tables.
				<li> DN as y axis unit can now only be selected for appropriate instruments.
    		    <li> The Instrument dialog now saves gain stage definition changes.
    		    <li> The Instrument dialog now verifies whether an instrument family already exists.
    		    <li> Many bug fixes.
    		</ul>
		<li> Version 3.3.0 (464):
			<ul>
    		    <li> Migrated the Impact data base access dialogs to SwiftUI. With that the migration to SwiftUI is complete.
   				<li> Improved the Impact Query dialog. The dialog clearly indicates if Spice ressources must be loaded first to enable a correct conversion of the event time.
   				<li> Added a context menu to the Query dialog to enable easier builds of range constraints (e.g. time ≥ x && time ≤ y).
   				<li> Other bug fixes.
    		</ul>
		<li> Version 3.3.0 (463):
			<ul>
    		    <li> The spreadsheet editor has been merged with the CSV export file dialog.
   				<li> Other bug fixes.
    		</ul>
		<li> Version 3.3.0 (462):
    		<ul>
    		    <li> Reorganized the Import menu in the menu bar. 
    		    <li> Fixed crashes associated with file selection dialogs.
    		    <li> Other bug fixes.
    		</ul>
		<li> Version 3.3.0 (Build 460):
			<ul>
				<li> Excludes events with clipped QD feature from Grid Statistics analysis.
				<li> Includes all bug fixes in the current stable branch (3.2.6).
			</ul>
		<li> Version 3.3.0 (Build 456):
			<ul>
		    	<li> Columns of all Viewer tables can be rearranged by the user (only supported in MacOS 14 Sonoma). A right click into the column's header opens a menu for downselecting columns.
		    	<li> Includes all bug fixes in the current stable branch (3.2.4).
			</ul>
		<li> Version 3.3.0 (Build 454):
			<ul>
		    	<li> Columns of the Spectrum and Line Viewer tables can be rearranged by the user (only supported in MacOS 14 Sonoma).
		    	<li> Implemented a work around to prevent crashes when starting an import on Intel Macs. Please note that I couldn't 
		    	     test this on an Intel Mac so far.
			</ul>      
	</ul>
</description>
]]></description>
            <enclosure url="https://impact.colorado.edu/Spectrum-beta.zip" length="76484783" type="application/octet-stream" sparkle:edSignature="TKtszyWFv7/IyUkI9R7r8x6PZNexfOq9/qx/Hg4KZe9le5MHXqbDB68YKnPXq8T+oqis5NyoBcMoZ1LSPogYAw=="/>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>